#### Contact

Mahmudabad, Sitapur 9455030291 (Mobile) ak7839131057@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/avnish7088 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Problem Solving
JAVASCRIPT INTERMEDIATE
Hrml

#### Certifications

Data science
CSS Crash Course For Beginners
HTML5, CSS3
Full Stack Developement

## **Avnish Kumar**

Java Full Stack Web Developer

Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India

## Summary

I possess the broad technical expertise and ability to handle multiple tasks and responsibilities to be a full-stack developer.

I can refer to the front-end user interface and presentation layer of a website or application that users interact with. I have proficient knowledge in HTML, CSS and JavaScript, Java to create responsive, user-friendly interfaces. I know how to use front-end frameworks like React, Angular to build scalable user interface. I can refer to the server-side of the back-end software of a website or application, where the logic, database, and data processing take place. I have knowledge of server-side programming languages such as MySQL, JAVA, MongoDB, and databases. I've been able to work with

server-side frameworks such as Django to develop and

manage the back-end of the application.

## Experience

Moreton Bay Regional Council
Moreton Bay Regional Council Entrepreneurship & Innovation: Web
Development
April 2023 - May 2023 (2 months)
India

The Moreton Bay Regional Council Entrepreneurship & Innovation internship program in Web Development is an exciting opportunity for aspiring developers to gain hands-on experience and develop their skills in a real-world setting. This internship is designed to provide students with practical experience in web development while working closely with experienced professionals in the field.

During the internship, participants will work on a variety of projects related to web development, including front-end and back-end web development, website maintenance, and website optimization. Participants will also have the opportunity to develop their skills in various programming languages and frameworks, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.

The internship program is open to students who are currently enrolled in a relevant degree program, or have recently graduated from a relevant program. Participants must have a strong foundation in web development, and should have experience working with programming languages and frameworks commonly used in web development.

This is a unique opportunity to gain hands-on experience in web development, work on real-world projects, and network with experienced professionals in the field. Participants will also gain a deeper understanding of the web development industry, and the various technologies and tools used in this field. Successful completion of the internship may lead to potential employment opportunities with the Moreton Bay Regional Council or other organizations in the field.

#### DEBU FILLING CENTER

Bio Diesel seals and supply manager July 2020 - April 2023 (2 years 10 months) Barabanki, Uttar Pradesh, India

#### HIMALAYA COLD STORAGE PVT LTD

Storage Specialist January 2019 - October 2019 (10 months) Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India

#### RISHIKA CONSTRUCTION LIMITED

Construction Supervisor January 2017 - June 2019 (2 years 6 months) Mathura, Uttar Pradesh, India

Britannia Industries Limited Computer Operator August 2016 - November 2017 (1 year 4 months) Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India

## Education

# NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF ELECTRONICS & INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (NIELIT)

O level, Computer Programming

Mack career NIIT

Java Full stack Web Developer , Computer Programming/ Programmer · (January 2023 - December 2023)

Chatrapati Sahuji Maharaj Kanpur University, Kanpur Bachelor of Commerce - BCom, Business/Commerce, General · (July 2015 - July 2018)

Kishan inter College

12th, Art/Art Studies · (July 2014 - July 2015)

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF ELECTRONICS & INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (NIELIT)

Ccc, Computer Science · (August 2019 - October 2019)